Michael Leon

Summary

Full-stack application developer with experience using popular front-end and back-end frameworks such as ReactJS and ExpressJS. Proven ability to create full-stack applications with efficient and thoughtfully designed data storage and clean, modern UIs. Always exploring and learning new technologies.

Skills

Languages JavaScript ● HTML ● CSS

Libraries/Frameworks React • Express

Databases MySQL● DynamoDB (NoSQL) ● MongoDB (NoSQL)

Cloud AWS • Azure

Other Git • Git + GitHub • REST API • JSON • XML • Agile Development • Confluence •

Zeplin

Professional Experience

Web Developer - JeffreyM, Seattle, WA

May 2020 – Present

Responsible for the maintenance of the JeffreyM website

- Work closely with the president and graphic designer of JeffreyM
 Fulfill requests to implement new features or five burs on the website
- Fulfil requests to implement new features or fix bugs on the website.
- Follow strict design guidelines

Technologies used: WordPress, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Zeplin https://jeffreym.com/

Freelance Web Developer – JeffreyM, Seattle, WA

Nov 2019 – Jan 2020

- Worked closely with the developer to develop the new company website based on a design document given by the graphic designer.
- Helped to set up and deploy WordPress onto the web host
- Created specific animations that were requested
- Launched the new company site upon finishing the project
 Technologies used: WordPress, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Zeplin

https://jeffreym.com/

Web Developer Intern – Ben Bridge Jewelers, Seattle, WA

Feb 2019 –

Jul 2019

- Developed the Marketing UI Application, User can create, edit, delete, and view events generated from the application. Package can be downloaded and used on a content asset on Salesforce.
- Fixed minor visual bugs on the website, and other minor tasks as assigned by mentor.

Technologies used: JavaScript, Node.JS, ExpressJS, MySQL, React, HTML, CSS, Python, Jira, Bitbucket

https://www.benbridge.com/

Projects

Event Crawler - Actokids

Jan 2019 – Mar 2019

- Developed a crawler for the client to scrape domains for events to be displayed in the admin UI
- Worked with API and Front-End teams to get the crawler data displaying properly on the UI

Technologies used: Python, AWS DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, Selenium, Beautifulsoup4,

Michael Leon

Dating App Feature Expansion – Meddle

Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

- Worked on a team of developers to create new features for an upcoming feature patch.
- Updated the user invitation functionality using deep linking,
- Connected user accounts together on successful invitation on firebase once the link was established.
- Created new UI for the contacts page.

Technologies used: React Native, Redux, Firebase, Branch.io

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/meddle-let-them-swipe/id1141606596?mt=8 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.meddle.meddle&hl=en US

Education

North Seattle College

Bachelor of Applied Science, Application Development

Academic honors: President's List

Focus Areas:

- Computer Science Fundamentals
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Object Oriented Programming
- Web Development
- Mobile Development
- Cloud Computing

University of Washington, Seattle Bachelor of Arts, History

Graduation: June 2019

Graduation: June 2015